<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>IPOB on The South Atlantic News</title>
        <link>https://thesanews.com/tags/ipob/</link>
        <description>Recent content in IPOB on The South Atlantic News</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thesanews.com/tags/ipob/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>IPOB: &#39;Nigeria must be politically decentralized&#39; — Adamu Garba boils over Fatima&#39;s death</title>
        <link>https://thesanews.com/p/ipob-nigeria-must-be-politically-decentralized-adamu-garba-boils-over-fatimas-death/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://thesanews.com/p/ipob-nigeria-must-be-politically-decentralized-adamu-garba-boils-over-fatimas-death/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://thesanews.com/p/ipob-nigeria-must-be-politically-decentralized-adamu-garba-boils-over-fatimas-death/adamu-garba.jpg" alt="Featured image of post IPOB: &#39;Nigeria must be politically decentralized&#39; — Adamu Garba boils over Fatima&#39;s death" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Despite the fact that Emma Powerful, the spokesman for Nigeria&amp;rsquo;s proscribed terrorist group, the Indigenious People of Biafra (IPOB), has come out to deny the murder of a northerner named Fatima; many political rights activists continue to condemn the incident, citing a perceived double standard in how the country&amp;rsquo;s social justice is administered. Many northerners, like Adamu Garba, an APC ex-member and presidential aspirant, have stated on social media that Nigeria cannot function without appropriate decentralization and power devolution to states and regions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fatima, a pregnant mother, was allegedly killed by IPOB terrorists in Anambra state, according to social media reports. The woman is claimed to be a native of Adamawa state and a devout Muslim who lives in Nigeria&amp;rsquo;s South-East political area. This heinous tragedy occurred just a week after a local congressman was assassinated. IPOB and its militant component, the Eastern Security Network, have come under fire for their increasing atrocities against both indigenous and non-indigenous people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adamu Garba took to social media to express his grief at the loss:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the whole world, there’s never been a terrorist organization that is as cowardly as IPOB. More importantly, no one is more prone to self-destruction than their silent supporters. The gruesomely murdered Fatima and her kids are from my state, Adamawa. I mean, are we really in the same country? The double standard is unimaginable. It seems like life in Nigeria has two grades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He went on to point out the hypocrisy of human rights activists on social media, citing the recent jungle justice against a professing Christian in Sokoto for alleged blasphemy against the Islamic religion&amp;rsquo;s prophet. Adamu Garba may have been annoyed by the episode, which got international notice; because according to him, no equivalent response was made to Fatima&amp;rsquo;s death. As a result, Adamu Garba recommended that power be dispersed in order to provide each individual a sense of belonging and security:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The faster we realize that Nigeria needs complete political decentralization and everyone should take care of their regions, the better for us. Why can’t people like Fatima and other people endangered in Anambra come back home since the government won’t protect or even care about them? We should stop pretending or trying to be politically correct. This country is not designed for equality and fairness for all citizens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Insecurity has increased in recent years in the West African country, spurred by religious and political ideologies. Despite the allocation of a trillion naira to combat the threat, insecurity persists in most parts of the country.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
