<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>The South Atlantic News</title>
        <link>https://thesanews.com/</link>
        <description>Recent content on The South Atlantic News</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thesanews.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Monkeypox: The forthcoming LGBT pride month may worsen the situation</title>
        <link>https://thesanews.com/p/monkeypox-the-forthcoming-lgbt-pride-month-may-worsen-the-situation/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://thesanews.com/p/monkeypox-the-forthcoming-lgbt-pride-month-may-worsen-the-situation/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://thesanews.com/p/monkeypox-the-forthcoming-lgbt-pride-month-may-worsen-the-situation/gay-monkeypox.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Monkeypox: The forthcoming LGBT pride month may worsen the situation" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Monkeypox, a non-endemic virus, is spreading across Europe with no known or established link between cases. Currently, over 100 cases have been identified in Germany, Switzerland, Spain, the UK, and other countries across Europe. Although monkeypox has its origins in the tropical jungles of West and Central Africa and is normally spread through intimate contact between humans and infected animals, scientists are baffled by the recent outbreak in Europe. Unrelated infections of people who appear to have no history together in different European countries could point to a mutant or mutation of the virus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scientific community is familiar with monkeypox as a virus. It is related to the chickenpox virus, which has been wiped out of the world in the last few decades. Monkeypox has a 3% mortality rate despite the availability of vaccinations. Regardless, the latest outbreak, which has been a mystery, could indicate that the virus has changed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Normally, an outbreak outside of West and Central Africa would be blamed on someone who recently visited West or Central Africa and came into contact with rodents like the Gambian rats. The new outbreak, however, could not be linked to anything outside of Europe. Indeed, new studies imply that it may have originated in a gay sauna in Madrid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enrinque Ruiz Escudero, Madrid&amp;rsquo;s cabinet minister for health, claimed that the 30 new cases in Spain could be related to a single adult sauna in Madrid. Infected people in the UK were also discovered to be gay. Thus, a certain international festival in Belgium alleges that the three cases discovered in Belgium were imported from contaminated nations, most likely Spain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The United Kingdom, which already has 20 cases, has encouraged gay men to watch for indications of the virus. Given that a gay pride celebration is expected to take place shortly in June, the UK government may be forced to restrict the LGTBQ+ community&amp;rsquo;s activities. This in itself is already causing chaos within the community and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>NBBF: Leadership crisis, threats, bans, and the decadence of basketball in Nigeria</title>
        <link>https://thesanews.com/p/nbbf-leadership-crisis-threats-bans-and-the-decadence-of-basketball-in-nigeria/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://thesanews.com/p/nbbf-leadership-crisis-threats-bans-and-the-decadence-of-basketball-in-nigeria/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://thesanews.com/p/nbbf-leadership-crisis-threats-bans-and-the-decadence-of-basketball-in-nigeria/men-team.jpg" alt="Featured image of post NBBF: Leadership crisis, threats, bans, and the decadence of basketball in Nigeria" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Federal Government of Nigeria has decided to prohibit all basketball activities within the country and all Nigerian basketball teams from competing in international competitions in order to combat the country&amp;rsquo;s sports decadence. Given reports that the Nigeria Basketball Federation&amp;rsquo;s (NBBF) administration is shambolic and lacking in direction, this move is not surprising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two leaders and two boards are said to rule the body, with neither side willing to cede control to the other. According to a press release from the Ministry of Youths and Sports Development, the men&amp;rsquo;s national team has vowed to stop playing for Nigeria unless a certain member is removed from the NBBF. Half of the D&amp;rsquo;Tigress players announced their desire to abandon the national team despite qualifying for the Women&amp;rsquo;s Basketball World Cup, confirming the body&amp;rsquo;s leadership turmoil. Despite repeated attempts to alleviate the issue and improve the sport in Nigeria, all efforts have failed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the Federal Government&amp;rsquo;s efforts to resolve the leadership situation, the FIBA&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;no politics in football&amp;rdquo; mantra prohibits governments from interfering in basketball activities. The basketball federation proceeded to follow the road of anarchy and instability in the absence of government guidance. A three-year ban on the Nigerian Premier Basketball League imposed by a court ruling added to the pandemonium, as sponsors sought safety by canceling their relationships. As a result, the disappointed government saw no other option except to impose a two-year ban on all basketball activities, which seemed justifiable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The women&amp;rsquo;s team, which had threatened to discontinue playing for Nigeria, published a press statement on May 20, 2022, expressing their unhappiness with the government&amp;rsquo;s decision to prevent them from competing in the Women&amp;rsquo;s Basketball World Cup in Australia. The D&amp;rsquo;Tigress squad highlighted its recent accomplishments in a news statement, including winning the Afrobasket 2021 championship in Cameroon. Despite the team&amp;rsquo;s previous threats to cease playing for the country, its new position, nevertheless, alludes to a possible solution to the crisis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recall that in 2010, Nigeria&amp;rsquo;s former president, Goodluck Jonathan, imposed a ban on national football teams participating in international games as a result of a prior humiliating World Cup performance. The ban forced the Nigerian Football Federation to reform, and the men&amp;rsquo;s national side won the AFCON cup against Burkina Faso in 2013. The government&amp;rsquo;s recent prohibition could be another historical occurrence that rhymes. Nonetheless, it is unlikely that the Buhari administration will overturn the decision anytime soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Insecurity: 1635 people kidnapped in Northern Nigeria</title>
        <link>https://thesanews.com/p/insecurity-1635-people-kidnapped-in-northern-nigeria/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://thesanews.com/p/insecurity-1635-people-kidnapped-in-northern-nigeria/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://thesanews.com/p/insecurity-1635-people-kidnapped-in-northern-nigeria/gunmen.png" alt="Featured image of post Insecurity: 1635 people kidnapped in Northern Nigeria" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;From explosions to kidnapping, Nigerians are fast becoming an endangered species in Sub-Saharan Africa. Although, according to HumAngle, N1 trillion was allocated for defense operations in 2022, the country still suffers from proscribed terrorist groups and bandits across the nation. StatiSense, a data company based in Nigeria, gives insight into the geographic demographics of these attacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to StatiSense, the North West and North Central are the major geopolitical regions where these crimes were perpetrated. The North accounted for 89.5% (1635) of all kidnappees in Nigeria, a staggering 545:64 ratio compared to the South, which accounted for 192. Surprisingly, the North East, which has been a base for terrorist attacks for the last decade, had only 4.46% of the northern kidnapees, unlike the North West and North Central, which topped the list with 837 and 725 kidnapees, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Considering the North West, the Abuja-Kaduna railway attack is a symbolic example of the deteriorated state of Kaduna&amp;rsquo;s security. The infamous attack was responsible for the deaths of eight Nigerians and kidnap of 168 passengers. The Abuja-Kaduna motor route bears the same gospel; news and video coverages have depicted the route as one for those as bold as Beauchamp. In addition, Katsina, and Zamfara were also part of the top 3 states with the highest number of kidnapees, all belonging to the North West.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, Niger State in the North Central continues to be identified in mainstream media with indiscriminate attacks on already improvished communities. Within the first 17 days of the first quarter, the Governor of the state, Sani Bello, stated that 300 communities had been attacked in Niger States and that 220 people had been killed while 200 were kidnapped, which included 3 Chinese expatriates. Sadly, these are just one of the many attacks that plague the state. Notwithstanding, it was also reported that the two most peaceful states in the country were Nassarawa and Gombe, which both belong to the North Central and North East respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a country which is already known for its notorious corruption and deteriorated sense of morals, the insecurity in the country will mitigate its development and probably deter future investors or expatriates from investing their time and money in a volatile security zone.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Russia: The US propose to manipulate and control African Governments against Russia</title>
        <link>https://thesanews.com/p/russia-the-us-propose-to-manipulate-and-control-african-governments-against-russia/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://thesanews.com/p/russia-the-us-propose-to-manipulate-and-control-african-governments-against-russia/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://thesanews.com/p/russia-the-us-propose-to-manipulate-and-control-african-governments-against-russia/usa-russia.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Russia: The US propose to manipulate and control African Governments against Russia" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The US has proposed a bill to manipulate or punish African governments and to control the mineral resources of the continent if the Russo-Sino influence on the continent continues to augment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the flying of Russian flags in Ethiopia to the rising numbers of Russo-Sino supporters in Africa, the West appears to be losing its foothold on the continent. Statistics keep pointing to the declining influence of the West in Africa such that; although in 2000, France was the top destination for the importation of goods into Africa; in 2022, over 70% of Africa’s imports are currently sourced from China. In addition, Russia is now Africa’s top source of arms importation and is responsible for 49% of arms exportation to Africa. The ongoing Russia-Ukraine conflict highlights the strategic importance of the continent in the struggle between the East and the West.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ongoing Ukraine-Russian crisis has also revealed the position of many African countries and their citizens concerning the crisis. During the UNGA held for a consensus decision on the Russian-Ukraine conflicts, the decisions of countries, especially in Africa, to abstain from the crisis could have been a source of irritation for the US. In addition, several African citizens, online, have also failed to criticize Russia’s role in the conflict, with many stating the double standards of the west and its corporations concerning the conflicts between Israel and Palestine. This places them on a different moral ground than the USA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the H.R.7311 bill, the USA will seek to control the natural resources, military bases, and security of the continent:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;.. control strategic sectors in Africa, such as mining and other forms of natural resource extraction and exploitation, military basing and other security cooperation agreements, and information and communications technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This could be likened to the undermining of African countries’ freedom of association and self-determination. It seems as though Africa would become a proxy ground for a war for resources between the West and the Eastern. Furthermore, the bill proposes to influence the politics of African countries and manipulate the governments to suit its agenda:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;..manipulate African governments and their policies, as well as the public opinions and voting preferences of African populations and diaspora groups, including those in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the enactment of the bill, annual reports will be made for the next five years on the activities of Russia on the continent, and strategies will be developed to counter activities that do not align with the interests of the US.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Archives</title>
        <link>https://thesanews.com/archives/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://thesanews.com/archives/</guid>
        <description></description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Privacy Policy</title>
        <link>https://thesanews.com/privacy-policy/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://thesanews.com/privacy-policy/</guid>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;privacy-policy-for-the-south-atlantic-news&#34;&gt;Privacy Policy for The South Atlantic News&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At The South Atlantic News, accessible from &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://thesanews.com&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://thesanews.com&lt;/a&gt;, one of our main priorities is the privacy of our visitors. This Privacy Policy document contains types of information that is collected and recorded by The South Atlantic News and how we use it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have additional questions or require more information about our Privacy Policy, do not hesitate to contact us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Privacy Policy applies only to our online activities and is valid for visitors to our website with regards to the information that they shared and/or collect in The South Atlantic News. This policy is not applicable to any information collected offline or via channels other than this website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;consent&#34;&gt;Consent&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By using our website, you hereby consent to our Privacy Policy and agree to its terms.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;information-we-collecth2&#34;&gt;Information we collect&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The personal information that you are asked to provide, and the reasons why you are asked to provide it, will be made clear to you at the point we ask you to provide your personal information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you contact us directly, we may receive additional information about you such as your name, email address, phone number, the contents of the message and/or attachments you may send us, and any other information you may choose to provide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you register for an Account, we may ask for your contact information, including items such as name, company name, address, email address, and telephone number.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-we-use-your-informationh2&#34;&gt;How we use your information&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use the information we collect in various ways, including to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide, operate, and maintain our website&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve, personalize, and expand our website&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understand and analyze how you use our website&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Develop new products, services, features, and functionality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Communicate with you, either directly or through one of our partners, including for customer service, to provide you with updates and other information relating to the website, and for marketing and promotional purposes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Send you emails&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find and prevent fraud&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;log-files&#34;&gt;Log Files&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The South Atlantic News follows a standard procedure of using log files. These files log visitors when they visit websites. All hosting companies do this and a part of hosting services&amp;rsquo; analytics. The information collected by log files include internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet Service Provider (ISP), date and time stamp, referring/exit pages, and possibly the number of clicks. These are not linked to any information that is personally identifiable. The purpose of the information is for analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users&amp;rsquo; movement on the website, and gathering demographic information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cookies-and-web-beacons&#34;&gt;Cookies and Web Beacons&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like any other website, The South Atlantic News uses &amp;lsquo;cookies&amp;rsquo;. These cookies are used to store information including visitors&amp;rsquo; preferences, and the pages on the website that the visitor accessed or visited. The information is used to optimize the users&amp;rsquo; experience by customizing our web page content based on visitors&amp;rsquo; browser type and/or other information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;our-advertising-partners&#34;&gt;Our Advertising Partners&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of advertisers on our site may use cookies and web beacons. Our advertising partners are listed below. Each of our advertising partners has their own Privacy Policy for their policies on user data. For easier access, we hyperlinked to their Privacy Policies below.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;advertising-partners-privacy-policies&#34;&gt;Advertising Partners Privacy Policies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may consult this list to find the Privacy Policy for each of the advertising partners of The South Atlantic News.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Third-party ad servers or ad networks uses technologies like cookies, JavaScript, or Web Beacons that are used in their respective advertisements and links that appear on The South Atlantic News, which are sent directly to users&amp;rsquo; browser. They automatically receive your IP address when this occurs. These technologies are used to measure the effectiveness of their advertising campaigns and/or to personalize the advertising content that you see on websites that you visit.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that The South Atlantic News has no access to or control over these cookies that are used by third-party advertisers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;third-party-privacy-policies&#34;&gt;Third Party Privacy Policies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The South Atlantic News&amp;rsquo;s Privacy Policy does not apply to other advertisers or websites. Thus, we are advising you to consult the respective Privacy Policies of these third-party ad servers for more detailed information. It may include their practices and instructions about how to opt-out of certain options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can choose to disable cookies through your individual browser options. To know more detailed information about cookie management with specific web browsers, it can be found at the browsers&amp;rsquo; respective websites.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ccpa-privacy-rights-do-not-sell-my-personal-information&#34;&gt;CCPA Privacy Rights (Do Not Sell My Personal Information)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under the CCPA, among other rights, California consumers have the right to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Request that a business that collects a consumer&amp;rsquo;s personal data disclose the categories and specific pieces of personal data that a business has collected about consumers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Request that a business delete any personal data about the consumer that a business has collected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Request that a business that sells a consumer&amp;rsquo;s personal data, not sell the consumer&amp;rsquo;s personal data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you make a request, we have one month to respond to you. If you would like to exercise any of these rights, please contact us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;gdpr-data-protection-rights&#34;&gt;GDPR Data Protection Rights&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would like to make sure you are fully aware of all of your data protection rights. Every user is entitled to the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The right to access – You have the right to request copies of your personal data. We may charge you a small fee for this service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The right to rectification – You have the right to request that we correct any information you believe is inaccurate. You also have the right to request that we complete the information you believe is incomplete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The right to erasure – You have the right to request that we erase your personal data, under certain conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The right to restrict processing – You have the right to request that we restrict the processing of your personal data, under certain conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The right to object to processing – You have the right to object to our processing of your personal data, under certain conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The right to data portability – You have the right to request that we transfer the data that we have collected to another organization, or directly to you, under certain conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you make a request, we have one month to respond to you. If you would like to exercise any of these rights, please contact us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;childrens-information&#34;&gt;Children&amp;rsquo;s Information&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another part of our priority is adding protection for children while using the internet. We encourage parents and guardians to observe, participate in, and/or monitor and guide their online activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The South Atlantic News does not knowingly collect any Personal Identifiable Information from children under the age of 13. If you think that your child provided this kind of information on our website, we strongly encourage you to contact us immediately and we will do our best efforts to promptly remove such information from our records.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Search</title>
        <link>https://thesanews.com/search/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://thesanews.com/search/</guid>
        <description></description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
