<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Nigeria on The South Atlantic News</title>
        <link>https://thesanews.com/tags/nigeria/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Nigeria on The South Atlantic News</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thesanews.com/tags/nigeria/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>IPOB: &#39;Nigeria must be politically decentralized&#39; — Adamu Garba boils over Fatima&#39;s death</title>
        <link>https://thesanews.com/p/ipob-nigeria-must-be-politically-decentralized-adamu-garba-boils-over-fatimas-death/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://thesanews.com/p/ipob-nigeria-must-be-politically-decentralized-adamu-garba-boils-over-fatimas-death/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://thesanews.com/p/ipob-nigeria-must-be-politically-decentralized-adamu-garba-boils-over-fatimas-death/adamu-garba.jpg" alt="Featured image of post IPOB: &#39;Nigeria must be politically decentralized&#39; — Adamu Garba boils over Fatima&#39;s death" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Despite the fact that Emma Powerful, the spokesman for Nigeria&amp;rsquo;s proscribed terrorist group, the Indigenious People of Biafra (IPOB), has come out to deny the murder of a northerner named Fatima; many political rights activists continue to condemn the incident, citing a perceived double standard in how the country&amp;rsquo;s social justice is administered. Many northerners, like Adamu Garba, an APC ex-member and presidential aspirant, have stated on social media that Nigeria cannot function without appropriate decentralization and power devolution to states and regions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fatima, a pregnant mother, was allegedly killed by IPOB terrorists in Anambra state, according to social media reports. The woman is claimed to be a native of Adamawa state and a devout Muslim who lives in Nigeria&amp;rsquo;s South-East political area. This heinous tragedy occurred just a week after a local congressman was assassinated. IPOB and its militant component, the Eastern Security Network, have come under fire for their increasing atrocities against both indigenous and non-indigenous people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adamu Garba took to social media to express his grief at the loss:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the whole world, there’s never been a terrorist organization that is as cowardly as IPOB. More importantly, no one is more prone to self-destruction than their silent supporters. The gruesomely murdered Fatima and her kids are from my state, Adamawa. I mean, are we really in the same country? The double standard is unimaginable. It seems like life in Nigeria has two grades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He went on to point out the hypocrisy of human rights activists on social media, citing the recent jungle justice against a professing Christian in Sokoto for alleged blasphemy against the Islamic religion&amp;rsquo;s prophet. Adamu Garba may have been annoyed by the episode, which got international notice; because according to him, no equivalent response was made to Fatima&amp;rsquo;s death. As a result, Adamu Garba recommended that power be dispersed in order to provide each individual a sense of belonging and security:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The faster we realize that Nigeria needs complete political decentralization and everyone should take care of their regions, the better for us. Why can’t people like Fatima and other people endangered in Anambra come back home since the government won’t protect or even care about them? We should stop pretending or trying to be politically correct. This country is not designed for equality and fairness for all citizens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Insecurity has increased in recent years in the West African country, spurred by religious and political ideologies. Despite the allocation of a trillion naira to combat the threat, insecurity persists in most parts of the country.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>NBBF: Leadership crisis, threats, bans, and the decadence of basketball in Nigeria</title>
        <link>https://thesanews.com/p/nbbf-leadership-crisis-threats-bans-and-the-decadence-of-basketball-in-nigeria/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://thesanews.com/p/nbbf-leadership-crisis-threats-bans-and-the-decadence-of-basketball-in-nigeria/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://thesanews.com/p/nbbf-leadership-crisis-threats-bans-and-the-decadence-of-basketball-in-nigeria/men-team.jpg" alt="Featured image of post NBBF: Leadership crisis, threats, bans, and the decadence of basketball in Nigeria" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Federal Government of Nigeria has decided to prohibit all basketball activities within the country and all Nigerian basketball teams from competing in international competitions in order to combat the country&amp;rsquo;s sports decadence. Given reports that the Nigeria Basketball Federation&amp;rsquo;s (NBBF) administration is shambolic and lacking in direction, this move is not surprising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two leaders and two boards are said to rule the body, with neither side willing to cede control to the other. According to a press release from the Ministry of Youths and Sports Development, the men&amp;rsquo;s national team has vowed to stop playing for Nigeria unless a certain member is removed from the NBBF. Half of the D&amp;rsquo;Tigress players announced their desire to abandon the national team despite qualifying for the Women&amp;rsquo;s Basketball World Cup, confirming the body&amp;rsquo;s leadership turmoil. Despite repeated attempts to alleviate the issue and improve the sport in Nigeria, all efforts have failed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the Federal Government&amp;rsquo;s efforts to resolve the leadership situation, the FIBA&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;no politics in football&amp;rdquo; mantra prohibits governments from interfering in basketball activities. The basketball federation proceeded to follow the road of anarchy and instability in the absence of government guidance. A three-year ban on the Nigerian Premier Basketball League imposed by a court ruling added to the pandemonium, as sponsors sought safety by canceling their relationships. As a result, the disappointed government saw no other option except to impose a two-year ban on all basketball activities, which seemed justifiable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The women&amp;rsquo;s team, which had threatened to discontinue playing for Nigeria, published a press statement on May 20, 2022, expressing their unhappiness with the government&amp;rsquo;s decision to prevent them from competing in the Women&amp;rsquo;s Basketball World Cup in Australia. The D&amp;rsquo;Tigress squad highlighted its recent accomplishments in a news statement, including winning the Afrobasket 2021 championship in Cameroon. Despite the team&amp;rsquo;s previous threats to cease playing for the country, its new position, nevertheless, alludes to a possible solution to the crisis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recall that in 2010, Nigeria&amp;rsquo;s former president, Goodluck Jonathan, imposed a ban on national football teams participating in international games as a result of a prior humiliating World Cup performance. The ban forced the Nigerian Football Federation to reform, and the men&amp;rsquo;s national side won the AFCON cup against Burkina Faso in 2013. The government&amp;rsquo;s recent prohibition could be another historical occurrence that rhymes. Nonetheless, it is unlikely that the Buhari administration will overturn the decision anytime soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Insecurity: 1635 people kidnapped in Northern Nigeria</title>
        <link>https://thesanews.com/p/insecurity-1635-people-kidnapped-in-northern-nigeria/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://thesanews.com/p/insecurity-1635-people-kidnapped-in-northern-nigeria/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://thesanews.com/p/insecurity-1635-people-kidnapped-in-northern-nigeria/gunmen.png" alt="Featured image of post Insecurity: 1635 people kidnapped in Northern Nigeria" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;From explosions to kidnapping, Nigerians are fast becoming an endangered species in Sub-Saharan Africa. Although, according to HumAngle, N1 trillion was allocated for defense operations in 2022, the country still suffers from proscribed terrorist groups and bandits across the nation. StatiSense, a data company based in Nigeria, gives insight into the geographic demographics of these attacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to StatiSense, the North West and North Central are the major geopolitical regions where these crimes were perpetrated. The North accounted for 89.5% (1635) of all kidnappees in Nigeria, a staggering 545:64 ratio compared to the South, which accounted for 192. Surprisingly, the North East, which has been a base for terrorist attacks for the last decade, had only 4.46% of the northern kidnapees, unlike the North West and North Central, which topped the list with 837 and 725 kidnapees, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Considering the North West, the Abuja-Kaduna railway attack is a symbolic example of the deteriorated state of Kaduna&amp;rsquo;s security. The infamous attack was responsible for the deaths of eight Nigerians and kidnap of 168 passengers. The Abuja-Kaduna motor route bears the same gospel; news and video coverages have depicted the route as one for those as bold as Beauchamp. In addition, Katsina, and Zamfara were also part of the top 3 states with the highest number of kidnapees, all belonging to the North West.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, Niger State in the North Central continues to be identified in mainstream media with indiscriminate attacks on already improvished communities. Within the first 17 days of the first quarter, the Governor of the state, Sani Bello, stated that 300 communities had been attacked in Niger States and that 220 people had been killed while 200 were kidnapped, which included 3 Chinese expatriates. Sadly, these are just one of the many attacks that plague the state. Notwithstanding, it was also reported that the two most peaceful states in the country were Nassarawa and Gombe, which both belong to the North Central and North East respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a country which is already known for its notorious corruption and deteriorated sense of morals, the insecurity in the country will mitigate its development and probably deter future investors or expatriates from investing their time and money in a volatile security zone.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
