<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Health on The South Atlantic News</title>
        <link>https://thesanews.com/categories/health/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Health on The South Atlantic News</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thesanews.com/categories/health/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Flooding has struck KwaZulu-Natal once more, displacing dozens of people</title>
        <link>https://thesanews.com/p/flooding-has-struck-kwazulu-natal-once-more-displacing-dozens-of-people/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://thesanews.com/p/flooding-has-struck-kwazulu-natal-once-more-displacing-dozens-of-people/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://thesanews.com/p/flooding-has-struck-kwazulu-natal-once-more-displacing-dozens-of-people/flooding.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Flooding has struck KwaZulu-Natal once more, displacing dozens of people" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;A life-threatening severe shower of rain has hit the KwaZulu-Natal area of South Africa just over a month after a previous disaster. Over 437 people were killed in the last flood, over 13,000 homes were partially or completely demolished, and property worth hundreds of millions of euros was destroyed. Despite the fact that people of KwaZulu-Natal are still attempting to recuperate from their losses, the rain has returned to shatter their life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Residents were told over the weekend that rainfall might reach 7.9 inches in some areas. The flood&amp;rsquo;s aftermath devastated roads, rendering them impassable and making escape impossible. In addition, many households have lost power, and many people are lacking in basic necessities like as food and water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several authorities expressed their sorrow for individuals who had been displaced by the water. Many people have pointed out that the displaced people have been without drinkable water for days because many water purification centers were destroyed during the flood. Despite this, 82 service centers have been established to meet the needs of the displaced people. In addition, security personnel have been actively involved in assisting the victims in their recovery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The geological setting of KwaZulu-Natal, according to geological research, makes it vulnerable to landslides and flooding. According to some accounts, the recent floods is also linked to global climate change and human impacts on the immediate environment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Monkeypox: The forthcoming LGBT pride month may worsen the situation</title>
        <link>https://thesanews.com/p/monkeypox-the-forthcoming-lgbt-pride-month-may-worsen-the-situation/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://thesanews.com/p/monkeypox-the-forthcoming-lgbt-pride-month-may-worsen-the-situation/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://thesanews.com/p/monkeypox-the-forthcoming-lgbt-pride-month-may-worsen-the-situation/gay-monkeypox.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Monkeypox: The forthcoming LGBT pride month may worsen the situation" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Monkeypox, a non-endemic virus, is spreading across Europe with no known or established link between cases. Currently, over 100 cases have been identified in Germany, Switzerland, Spain, the UK, and other countries across Europe. Although monkeypox has its origins in the tropical jungles of West and Central Africa and is normally spread through intimate contact between humans and infected animals, scientists are baffled by the recent outbreak in Europe. Unrelated infections of people who appear to have no history together in different European countries could point to a mutant or mutation of the virus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scientific community is familiar with monkeypox as a virus. It is related to the chickenpox virus, which has been wiped out of the world in the last few decades. Monkeypox has a 3% mortality rate despite the availability of vaccinations. Regardless, the latest outbreak, which has been a mystery, could indicate that the virus has changed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Normally, an outbreak outside of West and Central Africa would be blamed on someone who recently visited West or Central Africa and came into contact with rodents like the Gambian rats. The new outbreak, however, could not be linked to anything outside of Europe. Indeed, new studies imply that it may have originated in a gay sauna in Madrid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enrinque Ruiz Escudero, Madrid&amp;rsquo;s cabinet minister for health, claimed that the 30 new cases in Spain could be related to a single adult sauna in Madrid. Infected people in the UK were also discovered to be gay. Thus, a certain international festival in Belgium alleges that the three cases discovered in Belgium were imported from contaminated nations, most likely Spain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The United Kingdom, which already has 20 cases, has encouraged gay men to watch for indications of the virus. Given that a gay pride celebration is expected to take place shortly in June, the UK government may be forced to restrict the LGTBQ+ community&amp;rsquo;s activities. This in itself is already causing chaos within the community and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
