<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Flood on The South Atlantic News</title>
        <link>https://thesanews.com/tags/flood/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Flood on The South Atlantic News</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thesanews.com/tags/flood/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Flooding has struck KwaZulu-Natal once more, displacing dozens of people</title>
        <link>https://thesanews.com/p/flooding-has-struck-kwazulu-natal-once-more-displacing-dozens-of-people/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://thesanews.com/p/flooding-has-struck-kwazulu-natal-once-more-displacing-dozens-of-people/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://thesanews.com/p/flooding-has-struck-kwazulu-natal-once-more-displacing-dozens-of-people/flooding.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Flooding has struck KwaZulu-Natal once more, displacing dozens of people" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;A life-threatening severe shower of rain has hit the KwaZulu-Natal area of South Africa just over a month after a previous disaster. Over 437 people were killed in the last flood, over 13,000 homes were partially or completely demolished, and property worth hundreds of millions of euros was destroyed. Despite the fact that people of KwaZulu-Natal are still attempting to recuperate from their losses, the rain has returned to shatter their life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Residents were told over the weekend that rainfall might reach 7.9 inches in some areas. The flood&amp;rsquo;s aftermath devastated roads, rendering them impassable and making escape impossible. In addition, many households have lost power, and many people are lacking in basic necessities like as food and water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several authorities expressed their sorrow for individuals who had been displaced by the water. Many people have pointed out that the displaced people have been without drinkable water for days because many water purification centers were destroyed during the flood. Despite this, 82 service centers have been established to meet the needs of the displaced people. In addition, security personnel have been actively involved in assisting the victims in their recovery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The geological setting of KwaZulu-Natal, according to geological research, makes it vulnerable to landslides and flooding. According to some accounts, the recent floods is also linked to global climate change and human impacts on the immediate environment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
