<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Politics on The South Atlantic News</title>
        <link>https://thesanews.com/categories/politics/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Politics on The South Atlantic News</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thesanews.com/categories/politics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>A black Brazilian was smoked to death by the cops</title>
        <link>https://thesanews.com/p/a-black-brazilian-was-smoked-to-death-by-the-cops/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://thesanews.com/p/a-black-brazilian-was-smoked-to-death-by-the-cops/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://thesanews.com/p/a-black-brazilian-was-smoked-to-death-by-the-cops/black-lives.webp" alt="Featured image of post A black Brazilian was smoked to death by the cops" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;After being asphyxiated by officers at a police parade in Rio de Janeiro, the death of an unarmed black Brazilian named Genivaldo de Jesus Santos has sparked outrage across the country and on social media. The Brazilian man who was suffering from schizophrenia was subjected to police brutality, after being discovered with his health drugs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The victim was pushed down by police officers before being placed into a car, according to a video that has gone viral on the internet. Following that, a white, dense gas was seen rising in the car, with the victim struggling in the vehicle before finally succumbing. The savagery is comparable to the murder of George Flyod, which triggered a global Black Lives Matter protest. The death of Genivaldo de Jesus demonstrates that black people in Brazil may be targets of police abuse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In describing the incident, the cousin of Jesus Santos stated:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;They threw some kind of gas inside the truck and went to the police station, but my uncle was unconscious. He was sent to the hospital, but he did not survive.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The event occurred on Tuesday in Umbauba, only days after a police operation in the area resulted in the deaths of over 20 individuals in Rio de Janeiro. It has sparked protests in Umbauba, including roadblocks and the nonviolent use of fire to demand justice for the 38-year-old. In response, Brazilian President Jair Bolsonaro said he would contact the police to learn more about what happened and expressed his condolences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite this, an autopsy indicates that Jesus Santos died of &amp;ldquo;mechanical asphyxia,&amp;rdquo; a type of respiratory failure that matches the victim&amp;rsquo;s nephew&amp;rsquo;s story and the widely circulated recordings.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>2023: Peter Obi reveals a smear campaign against him and withdraws from the party&#39;s ticket battle</title>
        <link>https://thesanews.com/p/2023-peter-obi-reveals-a-smear-campaign-against-him-and-withdraws-from-the-partys-ticket-battle/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://thesanews.com/p/2023-peter-obi-reveals-a-smear-campaign-against-him-and-withdraws-from-the-partys-ticket-battle/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://thesanews.com/p/2023-peter-obi-reveals-a-smear-campaign-against-him-and-withdraws-from-the-partys-ticket-battle/peter-obi.webp" alt="Featured image of post 2023: Peter Obi reveals a smear campaign against him and withdraws from the party&#39;s ticket battle" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Despite appearing to have a large number of followers on social media, such that a #1MillionManMarch campaign was created in his favor; Nigerian presidential hopeful, Peter Obi, has abandoned his aspiration to run for one of the country&amp;rsquo;s major political parties, the People&amp;rsquo;s Democratic Party (PDP).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PDP and APC are the two biggest political parties in the oil-rich country, and they are comparable to the Republican and Democratic parties in the United States in terms of dominance. Winning the presidential primaries of any party, however, requires more than just making memos public. Money and, in most cases, tribal and religious feeling can influence the outcome of primaries in either of the two main parties, as documented in most primary elections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A major daily in the country, the Sahara Reporters, has previously claimed that Peter Obi might withdraw from the primaries. According to the source, the presidential aspirant may withdraw from the contest for the PDP presidential ticket due to a low likelihood of winning the party&amp;rsquo;s nomination. They stated that Peter Obi was willing to abandon the party for those who are willing and capable of spending money to obtain delegates&amp;rsquo; votes during the party&amp;rsquo;s primary this weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just as the day was coming to a conclusion, People Gazette claimed that Peter Obi had confirmed a gang up against him, effectively ruling him out of the race against the party&amp;rsquo;s other 14 confirmed hopefuls. He is anticipated to reveal the new platform from which he would launch his presidential campaign.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The identity of the party, however, has yet to be revealed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Russia: The US propose to manipulate and control African Governments against Russia</title>
        <link>https://thesanews.com/p/russia-the-us-propose-to-manipulate-and-control-african-governments-against-russia/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://thesanews.com/p/russia-the-us-propose-to-manipulate-and-control-african-governments-against-russia/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://thesanews.com/p/russia-the-us-propose-to-manipulate-and-control-african-governments-against-russia/usa-russia.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Russia: The US propose to manipulate and control African Governments against Russia" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The US has proposed a bill to manipulate or punish African governments and to control the mineral resources of the continent if the Russo-Sino influence on the continent continues to augment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the flying of Russian flags in Ethiopia to the rising numbers of Russo-Sino supporters in Africa, the West appears to be losing its foothold on the continent. Statistics keep pointing to the declining influence of the West in Africa such that; although in 2000, France was the top destination for the importation of goods into Africa; in 2022, over 70% of Africa’s imports are currently sourced from China. In addition, Russia is now Africa’s top source of arms importation and is responsible for 49% of arms exportation to Africa. The ongoing Russia-Ukraine conflict highlights the strategic importance of the continent in the struggle between the East and the West.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ongoing Ukraine-Russian crisis has also revealed the position of many African countries and their citizens concerning the crisis. During the UNGA held for a consensus decision on the Russian-Ukraine conflicts, the decisions of countries, especially in Africa, to abstain from the crisis could have been a source of irritation for the US. In addition, several African citizens, online, have also failed to criticize Russia’s role in the conflict, with many stating the double standards of the west and its corporations concerning the conflicts between Israel and Palestine. This places them on a different moral ground than the USA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the H.R.7311 bill, the USA will seek to control the natural resources, military bases, and security of the continent:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;.. control strategic sectors in Africa, such as mining and other forms of natural resource extraction and exploitation, military basing and other security cooperation agreements, and information and communications technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This could be likened to the undermining of African countries’ freedom of association and self-determination. It seems as though Africa would become a proxy ground for a war for resources between the West and the Eastern. Furthermore, the bill proposes to influence the politics of African countries and manipulate the governments to suit its agenda:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;..manipulate African governments and their policies, as well as the public opinions and voting preferences of African populations and diaspora groups, including those in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the enactment of the bill, annual reports will be made for the next five years on the activities of Russia on the continent, and strategies will be developed to counter activities that do not align with the interests of the US.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
