<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Peter Obi on The South Atlantic News</title>
        <link>https://thesanews.com/tags/peter-obi/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Peter Obi on The South Atlantic News</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thesanews.com/tags/peter-obi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>2023: Peter Obi reveals a smear campaign against him and withdraws from the party&#39;s ticket battle</title>
        <link>https://thesanews.com/p/2023-peter-obi-reveals-a-smear-campaign-against-him-and-withdraws-from-the-partys-ticket-battle/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://thesanews.com/p/2023-peter-obi-reveals-a-smear-campaign-against-him-and-withdraws-from-the-partys-ticket-battle/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://thesanews.com/p/2023-peter-obi-reveals-a-smear-campaign-against-him-and-withdraws-from-the-partys-ticket-battle/peter-obi.webp" alt="Featured image of post 2023: Peter Obi reveals a smear campaign against him and withdraws from the party&#39;s ticket battle" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Despite appearing to have a large number of followers on social media, such that a #1MillionManMarch campaign was created in his favor; Nigerian presidential hopeful, Peter Obi, has abandoned his aspiration to run for one of the country&amp;rsquo;s major political parties, the People&amp;rsquo;s Democratic Party (PDP).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PDP and APC are the two biggest political parties in the oil-rich country, and they are comparable to the Republican and Democratic parties in the United States in terms of dominance. Winning the presidential primaries of any party, however, requires more than just making memos public. Money and, in most cases, tribal and religious feeling can influence the outcome of primaries in either of the two main parties, as documented in most primary elections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A major daily in the country, the Sahara Reporters, has previously claimed that Peter Obi might withdraw from the primaries. According to the source, the presidential aspirant may withdraw from the contest for the PDP presidential ticket due to a low likelihood of winning the party&amp;rsquo;s nomination. They stated that Peter Obi was willing to abandon the party for those who are willing and capable of spending money to obtain delegates&amp;rsquo; votes during the party&amp;rsquo;s primary this weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just as the day was coming to a conclusion, People Gazette claimed that Peter Obi had confirmed a gang up against him, effectively ruling him out of the race against the party&amp;rsquo;s other 14 confirmed hopefuls. He is anticipated to reveal the new platform from which he would launch his presidential campaign.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The identity of the party, however, has yet to be revealed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
