<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Police Brutality on The South Atlantic News</title>
        <link>https://thesanews.com/tags/police-brutality/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Police Brutality on The South Atlantic News</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thesanews.com/tags/police-brutality/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>A black Brazilian was smoked to death by the cops</title>
        <link>https://thesanews.com/p/a-black-brazilian-was-smoked-to-death-by-the-cops/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://thesanews.com/p/a-black-brazilian-was-smoked-to-death-by-the-cops/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://thesanews.com/p/a-black-brazilian-was-smoked-to-death-by-the-cops/black-lives.webp" alt="Featured image of post A black Brazilian was smoked to death by the cops" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;After being asphyxiated by officers at a police parade in Rio de Janeiro, the death of an unarmed black Brazilian named Genivaldo de Jesus Santos has sparked outrage across the country and on social media. The Brazilian man who was suffering from schizophrenia was subjected to police brutality, after being discovered with his health drugs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The victim was pushed down by police officers before being placed into a car, according to a video that has gone viral on the internet. Following that, a white, dense gas was seen rising in the car, with the victim struggling in the vehicle before finally succumbing. The savagery is comparable to the murder of George Flyod, which triggered a global Black Lives Matter protest. The death of Genivaldo de Jesus demonstrates that black people in Brazil may be targets of police abuse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In describing the incident, the cousin of Jesus Santos stated:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;They threw some kind of gas inside the truck and went to the police station, but my uncle was unconscious. He was sent to the hospital, but he did not survive.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The event occurred on Tuesday in Umbauba, only days after a police operation in the area resulted in the deaths of over 20 individuals in Rio de Janeiro. It has sparked protests in Umbauba, including roadblocks and the nonviolent use of fire to demand justice for the 38-year-old. In response, Brazilian President Jair Bolsonaro said he would contact the police to learn more about what happened and expressed his condolences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite this, an autopsy indicates that Jesus Santos died of &amp;ldquo;mechanical asphyxia,&amp;rdquo; a type of respiratory failure that matches the victim&amp;rsquo;s nephew&amp;rsquo;s story and the widely circulated recordings.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
