<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>USA on The South Atlantic News</title>
        <link>https://thesanews.com/tags/usa/</link>
        <description>Recent content in USA on The South Atlantic News</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thesanews.com/tags/usa/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Salvador Ramos, 18, kills his grandma and students of former school in a Texas shooting</title>
        <link>https://thesanews.com/p/salvador-ramos-18-kills-his-grandma-and-students-of-former-school-in-a-texas-shooting/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://thesanews.com/p/salvador-ramos-18-kills-his-grandma-and-students-of-former-school-in-a-texas-shooting/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://thesanews.com/p/salvador-ramos-18-kills-his-grandma-and-students-of-former-school-in-a-texas-shooting/shooting.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Salvador Ramos, 18, kills his grandma and students of former school in a Texas shooting" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Salvador Ramos, an 18-year-old shooter, went on a shooting rampage in Uvalde, Texas, on Tuesday, May 24, 2022, killing 15 people at Robb Elementary School. The shooter was a former student at the school and was previously accused of murdering his grandmother.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The assailant, who was reportedly shot by security personnel, entered the primary school and brutally murdered children aged 5 to 11 years old as well as a teacher. A woman has also been reported as being in critical condition and is being treated at the San Antonio University Hospital. The hospital first announced it on social media, saying:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have received two patients from the shooting at Robb Elementary in Uvalde, one child and one adult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 66-year-old woman&amp;rsquo;s status was upgraded to critical in subsequent updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The president of the United States is likely to remark on the topic tonight, according to White House press secretary Karine Jean-Pierre, and has offered his heartfelt condolences to the affected family:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His prayers are with the families impacted by this awful event, and he will speak this evening when he arrives back at the White House.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, Texas Governor Greg Abbott praised those who assisted in stopping the shooting spree and expressed Texans&amp;rsquo; outrage over the tragic tragedy. The Texas Division of Emergency Management, according to the Governor, will provide the necessary resources to the relevant officials to help alleviate the effects of the shooting atrocity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Russia: The US propose to manipulate and control African Governments against Russia</title>
        <link>https://thesanews.com/p/russia-the-us-propose-to-manipulate-and-control-african-governments-against-russia/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://thesanews.com/p/russia-the-us-propose-to-manipulate-and-control-african-governments-against-russia/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://thesanews.com/p/russia-the-us-propose-to-manipulate-and-control-african-governments-against-russia/usa-russia.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Russia: The US propose to manipulate and control African Governments against Russia" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The US has proposed a bill to manipulate or punish African governments and to control the mineral resources of the continent if the Russo-Sino influence on the continent continues to augment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the flying of Russian flags in Ethiopia to the rising numbers of Russo-Sino supporters in Africa, the West appears to be losing its foothold on the continent. Statistics keep pointing to the declining influence of the West in Africa such that; although in 2000, France was the top destination for the importation of goods into Africa; in 2022, over 70% of Africa’s imports are currently sourced from China. In addition, Russia is now Africa’s top source of arms importation and is responsible for 49% of arms exportation to Africa. The ongoing Russia-Ukraine conflict highlights the strategic importance of the continent in the struggle between the East and the West.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ongoing Ukraine-Russian crisis has also revealed the position of many African countries and their citizens concerning the crisis. During the UNGA held for a consensus decision on the Russian-Ukraine conflicts, the decisions of countries, especially in Africa, to abstain from the crisis could have been a source of irritation for the US. In addition, several African citizens, online, have also failed to criticize Russia’s role in the conflict, with many stating the double standards of the west and its corporations concerning the conflicts between Israel and Palestine. This places them on a different moral ground than the USA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the H.R.7311 bill, the USA will seek to control the natural resources, military bases, and security of the continent:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;.. control strategic sectors in Africa, such as mining and other forms of natural resource extraction and exploitation, military basing and other security cooperation agreements, and information and communications technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This could be likened to the undermining of African countries’ freedom of association and self-determination. It seems as though Africa would become a proxy ground for a war for resources between the West and the Eastern. Furthermore, the bill proposes to influence the politics of African countries and manipulate the governments to suit its agenda:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;..manipulate African governments and their policies, as well as the public opinions and voting preferences of African populations and diaspora groups, including those in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the enactment of the bill, annual reports will be made for the next five years on the activities of Russia on the continent, and strategies will be developed to counter activities that do not align with the interests of the US.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
