<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Texas on The South Atlantic News</title>
        <link>https://thesanews.com/tags/texas/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Texas on The South Atlantic News</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thesanews.com/tags/texas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Salvador Ramos, 18, kills his grandma and students of former school in a Texas shooting</title>
        <link>https://thesanews.com/p/salvador-ramos-18-kills-his-grandma-and-students-of-former-school-in-a-texas-shooting/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://thesanews.com/p/salvador-ramos-18-kills-his-grandma-and-students-of-former-school-in-a-texas-shooting/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://thesanews.com/p/salvador-ramos-18-kills-his-grandma-and-students-of-former-school-in-a-texas-shooting/shooting.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Salvador Ramos, 18, kills his grandma and students of former school in a Texas shooting" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Salvador Ramos, an 18-year-old shooter, went on a shooting rampage in Uvalde, Texas, on Tuesday, May 24, 2022, killing 15 people at Robb Elementary School. The shooter was a former student at the school and was previously accused of murdering his grandmother.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The assailant, who was reportedly shot by security personnel, entered the primary school and brutally murdered children aged 5 to 11 years old as well as a teacher. A woman has also been reported as being in critical condition and is being treated at the San Antonio University Hospital. The hospital first announced it on social media, saying:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have received two patients from the shooting at Robb Elementary in Uvalde, one child and one adult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 66-year-old woman&amp;rsquo;s status was upgraded to critical in subsequent updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The president of the United States is likely to remark on the topic tonight, according to White House press secretary Karine Jean-Pierre, and has offered his heartfelt condolences to the affected family:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His prayers are with the families impacted by this awful event, and he will speak this evening when he arrives back at the White House.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, Texas Governor Greg Abbott praised those who assisted in stopping the shooting spree and expressed Texans&amp;rsquo; outrage over the tragic tragedy. The Texas Division of Emergency Management, according to the Governor, will provide the necessary resources to the relevant officials to help alleviate the effects of the shooting atrocity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
