<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Lukaku on The South Atlantic News</title>
        <link>https://thesanews.com/tags/lukaku/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Lukaku on The South Atlantic News</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thesanews.com/tags/lukaku/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Inter Milan could bring Romelu Lukaku back</title>
        <link>https://thesanews.com/p/inter-milan-could-bring-romelu-lukaku-back/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://thesanews.com/p/inter-milan-could-bring-romelu-lukaku-back/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://thesanews.com/p/inter-milan-could-bring-romelu-lukaku-back/lukaku.webp" alt="Featured image of post Inter Milan could bring Romelu Lukaku back" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to reports, Romelu Lukaku, the struggling Chelsea forward, has renewed Inter Milan&amp;rsquo;s interest in bringing him back to Italy this summer. According to multiple sources, Inter Milan CEO Giuseppe Marotta is excited to see the top-belgian striker don the club&amp;rsquo;s jersey once more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fabrizio Romano, a well-known sports journalist, confirmed the story on his social media account:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the next hours, the Inter board will meet with Romelu Lukaku&amp;rsquo;s counsel. The Belgian striker wishes to return to Inter, but Chelsea has yet to discuss the formula, salary, and other details.
Chelsea paid 115 million euros for Lukaku a year ago, so it&amp;rsquo;s a convoluted arrangement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite finishing the season as the club&amp;rsquo;s leading scorer with 15 goals in all competitions, the Belgian forward has been widely criticized for failing to justify his purchase price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The speculation of a probable return to Inter is not new. His controversial Sky Sports interview, in which he revealed his discontent with Chelsea&amp;rsquo;s current system of play and expressed his desire to return to Inter Milan, was chaotic and drew significant condemnation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inter Milan will find it tough to get a good deal out of Lukaku&amp;rsquo;s new Chelsea contract. Regardless, we&amp;rsquo;ll keep you updated on the situation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
