<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Crime on The South Atlantic News</title>
        <link>https://thesanews.com/categories/crime/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Crime on The South Atlantic News</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thesanews.com/categories/crime/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Insecurity: 1635 people kidnapped in Northern Nigeria</title>
        <link>https://thesanews.com/p/insecurity-1635-people-kidnapped-in-northern-nigeria/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://thesanews.com/p/insecurity-1635-people-kidnapped-in-northern-nigeria/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://thesanews.com/p/insecurity-1635-people-kidnapped-in-northern-nigeria/gunmen.png" alt="Featured image of post Insecurity: 1635 people kidnapped in Northern Nigeria" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;From explosions to kidnapping, Nigerians are fast becoming an endangered species in Sub-Saharan Africa. Although, according to HumAngle, N1 trillion was allocated for defense operations in 2022, the country still suffers from proscribed terrorist groups and bandits across the nation. StatiSense, a data company based in Nigeria, gives insight into the geographic demographics of these attacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to StatiSense, the North West and North Central are the major geopolitical regions where these crimes were perpetrated. The North accounted for 89.5% (1635) of all kidnappees in Nigeria, a staggering 545:64 ratio compared to the South, which accounted for 192. Surprisingly, the North East, which has been a base for terrorist attacks for the last decade, had only 4.46% of the northern kidnapees, unlike the North West and North Central, which topped the list with 837 and 725 kidnapees, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Considering the North West, the Abuja-Kaduna railway is a symbolic example of the deteriorated state of Kaduna&amp;rsquo;s security. The infamous attack was responsible for the deaths of eight Nigerians and kidnap of 168 passengers. The Abuja-Kaduna motor route bears the same gospel; news and video coverage have depicted the route as one for those as bold as Beauchamp. In addition, Katsina, and Zamfara were also part of the top 3 states with the highest number of kidnapees, all belonging to the North West.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, Niger State in the North Central continues to be identified in mainstream media with indiscriminate attacks on already improvished communities. Within the first 17 days of the first quarter, the Governor of the state, Sani Bello, stated that 300 communities had been attacked in Niger States and that 220 people had been killed while 200 were kidnapped, which included 3 Chinese expatriates. Sadly, these are just one of the many attacks that plague the state. Notwithstanding, it was also reported that the two most peaceful states in the country were Nassarawa and Gombe, which both belong to the North Central and North East respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a country which is already known for its notorious corruption and deteriorated sense of morals, the insecurity in the country will mitigate its development and probably deter future investors or expatriates from investing their time and money in a volatile security zone.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
